ADNAN CHOWDHURY

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

P (540) 449-1312

E adnan.chowdhury@outlook.com

A Murfreesboro, TN

in linkedin.com/in/adnan-chowdhury

Over 5 years of customer service experience • Strong multi-tasker and collaborator • Trained over 25 people Achieved 95% of projected sales in food service while being under-staffed • Opening team member for new business

PROJECTS

Sauti Africa Market Prices API • Back-End • Sep 2019 - Nov 2019

A stakeholder from Sauti Africa asked us to build an interactive experience for researchers & policymakers to interact with Sauti's Database on Market Prices and Developer API with extensive documentation for any developer to build any custom application or pursue data retrieval.

- Led pair-programming sessions to integrate external database to Node Server
- Planned daily & weekly objectives and coordinated with team on task queue
- Created end-to-end tests for API requests
- Designed and tested custom validation middleware for handling API requests
- Wrote comprehensive documentation for users and developers with GIF examples
- Conducted code reviews and incorporated feedback to improve development

Project Link: https://price-api.live/

Fifth Wheel • Front-End • Aug 2019

Fifth Wheel is a mock concept for an Airbnb-like app for RV owners. This project was built in under 4 days using React, SASS, Redux, Express, JWT, and PostgreSQL by 4 React developers and a Node/Express developer.

- Led two React developers to build and design user interface components
- Pair-programmed to developed global state management via Redux
- Integrated CRUD operations within Redux
- Assisted in usage of Semantic UI React library with SCSS
- Continuous integration and deployment of production site via Zeit
- Features of the App: Onboarding of users and usage of RV Marketplace

Project Link: https://5th-wheel.now.sh/

EXPERIENCE

Bartender • Kroger • Blacksburg, VA • June 2018 - May 2019

- Launch team member and helped establish a regular customer base
- Served over 20 customers in under 10 minutes
- Profiled and tasted over 200 craft beers and wines
- Informed customers of daily menu and provided recommendations
- Communicated with vendors to acquire the best and most popular items
- Organized special events for promotional products

Line Cook • Frank Theater • Blacksburg, VA • June 2016 - May 2018

- Maintained busy schedule working between line cook and dining services worker
- Synchronized with front of the house and theater side for optimal food production

Dining Services Worker • Virginia Tech • Blacksburg, VA • October 2013 - May 2018

- Multi-tasked between multiple food preparation stations
- Led a team of 10+ workers during absence of supervisor
- Trained numerous workers on various tasks and communication
- High volume work environment requiring focus and prioritization

EDUCATION

Lambda School, 2019-2020 Full Stack Web Development & Computer Science

Lambda School is a Computer Science & Software Engineering Academy

Virginia Tech, 2009-2013 Completed 3 years for B.S. in Computer Engineering

TECH STACK

- JavaScript
- Python
- React
- React hooks
- HTML/CSS
- Django
- Express
- Redux
- SQL
- Sass

TOOLS

- Git
- GitHub
- Command Line Interface as Bash
- Windows (also Linux via WSL)
- Data Structures & Algorithms
- VS Code
- Slack
- Trello
- Zeit
- Netilfly
- Heroku
- Agile(Scrum)